<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cheatsheets</title>
    <link>http://kimgoetzke.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cheatsheets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kimgoetzke.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Regex</title>
      <link>http://kimgoetzke.github.io/other/regex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kimgoetzke.github.io/other/regex/</guid>
      <description>Key resources Compose and testing expressions: https://regex101.com/ Regex number range generator: Regex Numeric Range Generator — Regex Tools — 3Widgets Shorthands for regex There are several pre-defined shorthands for the commonly used character sets:
\d is any digit, short for [0-9] \s is a whitespace character (including tab and newline), short for [ \t\n\x0B\f\r] \w is an alphanumeric character (word), short for [a-zA-Z_0-9] \b is a word boundary A word boundary doesn&amp;rsquo;t match any specific character, it rather matches a boundary between an alphanumeric character and a non-alphanumeric character - for example, a whitespace character - or a boundary of the string (the end or the start of it) - examples: \ba matches any sequence of alphanumeric characters that starts with &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo;, a\b matches any sequence of alphanumeric characters that ends with &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo; \ba\b matches a separate &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo; preceded and followed by non-alphanumeric characters There are also counterparts of these shorthands that are equivalent to the restrictive sets, and match everything except for the characters mentioned above:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>http://kimgoetzke.github.io/docker/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kimgoetzke.github.io/docker/notes/</guid>
      <description>Install Docker Windows Linux </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Docker commands</title>
      <link>http://kimgoetzke.github.io/docker/docker-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kimgoetzke.github.io/docker/docker-commands/</guid>
      <description>Basic Docker commands List all local images docker images docker image ls The parameter -q will ensure only Ids are listed. docker image ls -q List all containers docker ps The parameter -a will include stopped containers. docker ps -a List all and don&amp;rsquo;t truncate columns (for example, to see entrypoints)
docker ps --no-trunc Remove a single image docker image rm [image_id] Remove all image This command will result in an error if an image currently used in a container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Subsystem for Linux</title>
      <link>http://kimgoetzke.github.io/linux/wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kimgoetzke.github.io/linux/wsl/</guid>
      <description>Useful resources Basic commands for WSL: Basic commands for WSL | Microsoft Learn Useful commands List all available Linux distributions wsl --list --online List of installed Linux distributions wsl --list --verbose Update WSL wsl --update </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
